前情提要
Previously on
Those About to Die...
你在找竞技场，是吗？
You seek the arena, do you?
- 来了- 只是想卖我们的安达卢西亚人。
- Come.
- Just looking to sell our Andalusians.
比赛结束后我会和芬布里亚谈谈。
I'll speak to Fimbria
after the race.
你哥哥今天做得很好，你没有。
Your brother did well
today, you did not.
你玩忽职守
You neglect your duty
睡在你床上的犹太女王
for that Judean queen
who sleeps in your bed.
- 你妻子的股份？- 那是什麽？
- Your wife's shares?
- What is that?
财富，地位，权力。
Wealth, position, power.
五百股蓝色阵营的股票。
500 shares of the Blue Faction.
为什么柯克的战车会散架？
Why did Kirko's
chariot fell apart?
你可以走了
You can leave.
诸神在上
By the Gods...
你在干什麽？
What are you doing?
你想干什么？
What do you want?
- 这是什麽？- 一个开口销，切到一半。
- What's this?
- One cotter pin, cut halfway through.
我的赛车搭档死了。
My racing partner is dead.
如果我没换装备的话我会的。
And I would be if I
hadn't switched rigs.
这是你的补救措施吗
Is this one of your fixes?
天蝎座输了，你就赚大钱。
Scorpus loses, you collect big.
我摔断了几根骨头或者脖子，让它看起来像真实的。
I break a few bones or my
neck, to make it look real.
当然不是
No, of course it's not.
我告诉过你，我对我们俩有更大的计划
I told you, I have much
bigger plans for the both of us
而不是几场作弊的比赛
than a few more rigged races.
那就查出是谁破坏了我的装备
Then find out who
sabotaged my rig,
杀了他们
and kill them.
哦...
Oh...
不错啊
Nice.
看起来就像我的马，因西塔斯。
Looks just like my
horse, Incitatus.
走了从今天开始拿走你的奖金。
Go. And take your
winnings from today.
别把我当回事
Don't take me for granted.
我不知道
I don't.
是的好孩子
Yes. Good boy.
你怎么认识安达卢西亚人的？
How do you know Andalusians?
我开车送他们来的。很久以前的事了
I drove them. A long time ago.
你比赛了？
You raced?
嗯，没有马能和我们的安达卢西亚马匹敌。
Well, there are no horses out
there to equal our Andalusians.
他们怎么样？
How are they?
索纳和西斯塔的腿被碎片切掉了。
Sorna and Sista got their
legs cut from the debris.
我们得让他们休息一周。
We'll have to rest
them for a week.
安达卢西亚人？
Andalusians, huh?
- 是的- 哈你
- Yes.
- Huh.
加夫罗斯对安达卢西亚人评价很高，我认为他们是猪。
Gavros has a high opinion of
Andalusians, I think they're pigs.
他们比你的海湾更快，更坚固，更灵活。
They're faster than your
Bays, sturdier, and more nimble.
如果他们是猪，那你的海湾是什么？
If they're pigs, what does
that make your Bays?
听听这孩子说的。他让你想起了谁？
Listen to the boy. Who
does he remind you of?
我想的是我，但现在...
I was thinking me, but now...
我在想你。
I'm thinking you.
明天下午，
Tomorrow afternoon,
我去看看你的安达卢西亚人。
I'll take a look at
your Andalusians.
加弗罗斯
Gavros!
你哥哥很会说话。
Your brother has
a way with words.
明天下午你要为天蝎座赛马。
Your running your horse for
Scorpus tomorrow afternoon.
干得好，弟弟。
Well done, little brother.
想象一下我们的马在罗马为蓝军效力。
Imagine our horse is
running for the Blues in Rome.
你住在哪里？
Where do you stay?
我知道一个地方。跟我来
I know a place. Follow me.
Tenax的人。
One of Tenax's.
这一个比其他的害虫少。
This one has fewer
vermin than the others.
Tenax是谁？
Who's Tenax?
你很快就会知道了。
You'll find out soon enough.
谢谢你加弗罗斯
Thank you, Gavros.
一个月九个塞斯特斯。
Nine sesterces a month.
每个.
Each.
我只有两个。
I only have two.
你把钱花在什么地方了？
What did you spend it on?
你在床上待的时间已经够长了，方索阿。
You've already spent
enough time in a bed, Fonsoa.
现在你发言
Now, you get the floor.
怎么回事？
What's happening?
- 爸爸！- 不不求你了
- Papa!
- No, no, please!
谁让你这么做的
Who told you to do this?
不是我干的。泰纳克斯，拜托。相信我
I didn't do it. Tenax,
please. Believe me.
所以比起我你更害怕那个人。
So you're more afraid of
whoever it was than you are of me.
不求你了求你了我对此一无所知。
No, please, please. I
know nothing about this.
相信我，求你了...
Believe me, please...
你太让我失望了
You disappoint me.
- 不！不！不！不，不，不！- 我知道是谁
- No! No, no, no!
- I know who!
他有一头红发，当时他在商店里。
He had red hair and
he was in the shop.
他说这是给你的惊喜，爸爸。
He said it was a
surprise for you, Papa.
说这是个秘密
Said it was a secret.
你真走运
Lucky you.
是的，我会的
Yes!
今天是你的大日子，对吧？
It's your day, yeah?
你刚来罗马，对吧？
You're new to Rome, yes?
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是Tenax
I'm Tenax.
问问周围的人
Ask around.
人们会建议你对我有礼貌。
People will suggest
you be polite to me.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
这里的规矩是
The way things work
around here is that
在你搞战车比赛之前
before you fuck
with a chariot race,
你好好问我。
you ask me nicely.
如果你想用一种可能会杀死
And if you want to do
it in a way that might kill
他是罗马最有价值的车夫
the most valuable
charioteer in Rome
他碰巧是我的朋友
who happens to be my friend,
那我会拒绝
then I'd say no.
我就割了你的蛋蛋。
And I'd cut off your balls.
你叫什么名字？
Your name again?
Tenax
Tenax.
我听说过你
I heard of you.
你在你的小世界里很强大。
You're very powerful
in your little world.
雇我的人
The person who hired me
来自一个更大的世界
is from a much,
much bigger world.
也许这个人会保护你。
Perhaps this person
will protect you.
再说吧
We'll see.
走吧卢修斯
Come on, Lucius.
他甚至没有站起来。
He didn't even stand up.
你应该杀了他。
You should have killed him.
我会的
I will.
首先，我得处理雇他的人。
First, I have to deal with
the one who hired him.
我们要怎么找出是谁？
How do we find out who it was?
他刚告诉我的。
He just told me.
我不会送你走的
I will not send you away.
但你必须这么做
But you must.
我很快就要当皇帝了
I'll be Emperor soon.
没有人会挑战我。
No one will challenge me.
如果你哥哥坐上了教长之位，那我和我的人民怎么办？
If your brother takes the curule
chair, what then of me and my people?
没有什么比
Nothing would
delight him more than
让他的竞技场充满了我们的鲜血
filling his arena
with our blood.
不是他的
It's not his.
是罗马的。
It's Rome's.
是我的
It's mine.
待在这
Stay here.
在罗马。
In Rome.
你们两个出去
You two, out.
你杀了那个想杀我的小混蛋吗
Did you kill the little
shit who tried to kill me?
不完全是
Not exactly.
图密善下令破坏你的战车。
It was Domitian who ordered
your chariot sabotaged.
图密善？
Domitian?
他为什么要我死？
Why would he want me dead?
他只是需要点钱，所以他...
He just needed
some money, so he...
增加了一点胜算
nudged the odds a bit.
为什么图密善需要钱？
Why would Domitian need money?
他的家族统治着整个世界。
His family rule
the fucking world.
是也不是
Yes and no.
他父亲把他管得很严。
His father keeps
him on a tight leash.
他是两个儿子中最小的一个。
Remember, he is the
lesser of the two sons.
他必须非常小心地对待他父亲。
He has to tread very
carefully with his father.
他欠了罗马各地赌场几百万。
He owes millions to betting
taverns all over Rome.
告诉我们他有多绝望。
Which tell us just how
desperate he's become.
这是好消息，真的。
It's good news, really.
这是我们需要的最后一块拼图
This is the final piece
of the puzzle we need
得到我们的派系
to get our faction.
- 你说什么？怎么做？
What? How?
好吧...
Well...
你是我们历史上最好的车手
in you, we have the
best driver in history.
- 同意了- 当我卖掉蓝色的股份时
- Agreed.
- And when I sell the shares in the Blue,
我们就有足够的资金来建立自己的派系
we'll have enough to
fund our own faction.
那么我们只需要得到许可
Then, all we need is permission
从市政厅卢迪，
from the Aedile Ludi,
游戏之王，谁是？
Master of the Games,
who happens to be?
贵族，但是穷
The noble, but skint
图密善，皇帝的儿子。
Domitian, son of the Emperor.
是的，我会的
Yes!
这就是奴隶的下场
That's what happens to slaves
当他们不接受命运的时候
when they don't
accept their fate.
拿着
Take them.
- 不！不！不！- 夸梅
- No!
- Kwame.
看着我坚强点
Look at me. Be strong.
坚强点
Be strong.
- 坚强点- 救命啊！
- Be strong.
- Help!
奥拉，照顾好她！
Aura, look after her!
夸梅不！不！不！不！不！不！
Kwame! No! No!
不！不！不！
No!
法里德
Ah, Farid.
你有什么要给我的？
What do you have for me?
好好欣赏吧。
Feast your eyes.
上帝保佑
By the Gods.
我听说过这样的野兽，但认为它们是虚构的。
I've heard of such beasts, but
thought they were imaginary.
他是真实的。你要为他付真实的钱。
Oh, he's real. And you're
going to pay real money for him.
他在抓捕过程中杀了两个人，
He killed two men in the taking,
并在运输过程中撕裂了另一个
and ripped apart another
during the transport.
好吧，我完蛋了。
Well, I'm done for.
我已经喜欢上他了。
I like him already.
他是谁？
Who is he?
夸梅，抓他的人。
Kwame, his captor.
他害怕野兽受到恶魔的保护。
He fears the beast is
protected by demons.
我害怕爪子和牙齿。
I fear claws and teeth.
不是魔法。
Not magic.
你应该两个都害怕。
You should fear both.
四百
Four hundred.
五
Five.
稍等
One moment.
一些努米底亚人正在出售珍珠。
Some Numidian is selling pearls.
啊
Ah.
新买的奴隶，会被带到哪里去？
Newly bought slaves,
where would they be taken?
你好
Salam.
你有多少珍珠？
How many pearls do you have?
你卖了那辆车赚的钱呢？
And the money you got
from the one you sold?
她还能有什么？
What else might she have?
你看不出来吗？
Can't you see?
嘘！走！
Psst! Go!
想想我哥哥要把他从塔佩岩上扔下去。
And to think my brother were to
throw him from the Tarpeian Rock.
那会是多么的浪费啊。
What a waste that
would have been.
- 弗拉玛- 弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯
- Flamma.
- Flavius Domitianus.
他们还喂得好吗？
Are they still feeding you well?
是的
Yes.
- 女人？- 我选。
- Women?
- My pick.
在每月的卡伦德和伊德斯。
On the Kalends and
the Ides of each month.
好.
Good.
新来的。
New arrivals.
好.
Good.
太轻了。即使是退休人员。
Too light. Even for Retiarius.
我见过他打架。
I've seen him fight.
他很快。
He's fast.
据说他赤手空拳杀死了一头狮子。
He's said to have killed
a lion with his bare hands.
赤手空拳？
With his bare hands?
我想看看你能做什么。
I'd like to see what you can do.
把他和这个放在一起。
Put him with this one.
维果
Viggo.
中等系绳。
Medium tether.
他不能这么做。
He's not allowed to do that.
一把短剑。
A gladius.
停下来！
Stop!
别说了
Stop.
原谅我，弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯。
Forgive me, Flavius Domitianus.
Viggo有追随者。
Viggo has a following.
让弗拉玛在众人面前杀了他不是更好吗
Isn't it perhaps better to let
Flamma kill him before a crowd?
很好.
Very well.
一头狮子。没有武器。
A lion. Without a weapon.
当然是谎言。但很大胆。
A lie, of course.
But a bold one.
北非充满了肮脏的害虫和狗，
North Africa, filled with
filthy vermin and dogs,
被我威严的父亲安抚
pacified by my august father.
不过，谢天谢地，没有太多的安抚。
But, thankfully, not
pacified too much.
告诉我
So, tell me.
你赤手空拳能杀死什么？
What could you kill
with you bare hands?
克制！
Restrain!
买下他我们要好好表现他的死。
Buy him. We'll make a
good show of his death.
跟我
With me.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
别担心他会来的
Don't worry. He'll be here.
他来了
Here he comes.
对安达卢西亚人来说太小了。
They're small for Andalusians.
马跑得快不是因为它们的体型。
It is not their size
that makes horses fast.
没有鞭子。他们没有它跑得更好。
And no whip. They
run better without it.
啊！
Yah!
开球开球
Hut, hut, hut.
哇哦
Whoa.
他们很快。
They're fast.
喔。
Whoo.
啊！
Yah!
- 是的，在这里，你...... - 嘿！嘿！
- Yes, here, you...
- Hey!
你考虑过我的提议了吗
Have you thought about my offer?
是的，我有。
Yes, I have.
两万塞斯特斯换一万
Twenty-thousand
sesterces for the ten,
但你们三个继续做马房
but the three of you
stay on as stable hands
最大限度地利用他们
to get the most out of them.
- 我们接受。- 两个提议。
- We accept.
- Both offers.
去他妈的。我们说好要回去的。
The hell we do. We
agreed to go back.
埃利亚看看周围
Elia, look around.
- 你真的想回去吗？- 是的
- Do you really want to go back?
- Yes.
我们在马克西姆斯马戏团这里是天蝎座
We're at Circus Maximus
and this is Scorpus.
他想买下你的马然后雇我们。
He's trying to buy
your horses and hire us.
没错他想把我们困在这个城市的下水道里。
Exactly. He wants to trap
us in this sewer of a city.
两万塞斯特斯。
Twenty thousand sesterces.
我会把钱。
I will take the money.
但我们同意卖了马回去。
But we agreed to sell
the horses and go back.
我们真的可以成为这里的某个人。
We could really be someone here.
为我们自己扬名立万。
Make a name for ourselves.
马，你想要多少都行。
Horses, as many as you want.
我在贝提卡有所有想要的马。
I have all the horses I
want back in Baetica.
小伙子们
Boys.
天蝎座正在等待。
Scorpus is waiting.
是的
Yes.
我们投票。
We vote.
我进来了
I'm in.
是的
Yes.
我不投票。我要走了
I am not voting. I'm leaving.
埃利亚
Elia!
他会想通的
He'll come around.
我们说好的
We have a deal.
小混蛋也留下，好吗？
The little shit
stays as well, yes?
是的
Yes.
我刚刚驾驶了我一生中最快的马。
I have just driven the
fastest horses in my life.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
他们乘着飞马的翅膀飞翔。
They fly on the
wings of Pegasus.
所以我就买了。
So I bought them.
好吧，用你的钱。
Well, with your money.
- 所以你加入了？- 我当然加入。
- So you're in?
- Of course I'm in.
我一直都在
I've always been in.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
天蝎座买马不是很正常吗？
Isn't it normal for
Scorpus to buy horses?
用你的钱，是的。
With your money, yes.
这是他自己的事。
This was on his own.
你觉得天蝎座会离开我们去别的阵营吗
Do you think Scorpus is
leaving us for another faction?
他在策划什么事。
He's up to something.
领事有一个人在这里要求见你。
Consul. There is a man
here requesting an audience.
Tenax，一个平民。
Tenax, a plebeian.
不当然没有
No, of course not.
把他交给我的一个客户。
Send him to one of my clients.
他很坚持。
He is very insistent.
他说他有一些关于蓝派的东西要给你。
He says he has something to
offer you regarding the Blue Faction.
蓝派五百股。
Five hundred shares
of the Blue Faction.
你怎么拿到这些的
How did you get these?
赌债
A gambling debt.
你为什么带着他们来找我
Why did you come
to me with them?
因为这些股份会让你再次成为蓝派的领导者。
Because these shares will make you
lead owner of the Blue Faction again.
意思是，你会比其他人付更多的钱。
Meaning, you'll pay more
for them than anyone else.
- 也许吧- 当然。
- Perhaps.
- For certain.
你当盟主的时候，蓝派很繁荣。
The Blue Faction was prosperous
when you were lead owner.
卡尔托尼亚嫁给老利纽斯已经不是什么秘密了
It's no secret that
Caltonia married old Linius
因为他们的股份加起来
because of their
combined shares.
后来，他死了，她仍然是主要的所有者。
And then, he died, and
she remained lead owner.
你想要回那个职位也不是什么秘密了。
And it's no secret that
you want that position back.
七十万塞斯特斯。
700,000 sesterces.
- 太荒唐了- 八十万塞斯特斯
- That's absurd.
- 800,000 sesterces.
这是一种侮辱性的讨价还价方式。走开
This is an insulting
way to bargain. Be off.
如你所愿
As you wish.
我猜卡托尼亚会想永久巩固她的地位，
I assume Caltonia will want to
permanently solidify her position as
领导者。
lead owner.
别说了
Stop.
五十万
Five hundred thousand.
九
Nine.
好吧
Fine.
九十万。
Nine hundred thousand.
但我们告诉全世界是五个。
But we tell the
world it was five.
如你所愿
As you wish.
好好享受你的复仇吧领事
Enjoy your revenge, Consul.
卑鄙的人。
Vile man.
为什么他卖给我们而不是她？
Why did he sell to
us and not to her?
因为他正确地衡量了我对Caltonia的仇恨
Because he correctly
measured my hatred of Caltonia
我想成为领头羊的愿望
with my desire to be lead owner.
当她知道这件事时，她会做什么样的表情。
What a face she'll make
when she learns of this.
很美，不是吗？
Beautiful, isn't it?
超越。
Beyond.
如果这些犹太人用他们必须建造的设施发动战争，
If these Judeans waged war with
the same facility they have to build,
我们永远也不会打败他们
we never would
have defeated them.
弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯
Flavius Domitianus.
谢谢你同意见我
Thank you for
agreeing to see me.
你可以为此感谢天蝎座。
You can thank Scorpus for that.
别告诉我你是来讨债的。
Please tell me you're not
here to ask for what I owe you.
号
No.
不，我早就意识到
No, I've long since
come to realize
接受皇室的赌注
that taking bets from
the Imperial family
只不过是一种税收形式。
is no more than
a form of taxation.
好.
Good.
说话
Speak.
这次谈话应该在四只眼睛的注视下进行。
This conversation should
be held under four eyes.
走了
Go.
听着，我不在乎你欠我什么。
Look, I don't care
about what you owe me.
我不在乎你试图操纵
I don't care that
you tried to rig
昨天的比赛，无论如何。
the race yesterday, at all.
它只告诉我一件事。
It just tells me one thing.
你需要钱。
You need money.
很多钱。
Lots of money.
你在玩一个危险的游戏。
You play a dangerous game here.
你也是
As do you.
粮食供应。
The grain supply.
食物暴动野心
Food riots. Ambition.
他们都很危险
They're all dangerous.
我不知道该不该听你的
I don't know whether
I should listen to you
或者干脆杀了你
or simply have you killed.
你可以两样都做
You could do both.
为什么不先听我说？
Why not listen to
what I have to say first?
- 很好. - 像你一样，我也是个有野心的人。
- Very well.
- Like you, I'm an ambitious man.
我的搭档，伟大的御马师，天蝎座，和我
My partner, the great
charioteer, Scorpus, and I
希望组建一个新的赛车派系
wish to form a
new racing faction.
他要脱离蓝军？
He would break
away from the Blue?
他们为他做了那么多？
After everything
they've done for him?
他很有野心。
He's ambitious.
和我一样和你一样
Same as me, same as you.
我很享受这样。继续
I'm enjoying this. Continue.
天蝎座和我有足够的钱建立一个新的派系，
Scorpus and I have the
money to start a new faction,
我们最近得到了一些马，非常惊人的马，
and we've recently acquired
some horses, astonishing horses,
这将确保胜利。
that will ensure victories.
我们现在只需要得到帝国的许可
All we need now is
Imperial permission
在马克西姆斯竞技场和他们比赛
from you as Aedile Ludi to
race them at the Circus Maximus.
这对我有什么好处
And how would this benefit me?
一条钱的河流。
A river of money.
一半的所有权是秘密的，它将产生一切。
Half ownership in secret
and all that it will yield.
胜利的钱包，门百分比。
Victory purses, gate percentage.
座位费，种马费，投注收入，
Seat fees, stud fees,
betting proceeds,
以及股票本身的价值。
as well as the value of
the shares themselves.
这些“惊人的马”？
These "astonishing horses"?
安达卢西亚人用天蝎座的话来说，
Andalusians. With, in
the words of Scorpus,
“飞马的翅膀。"
"The wings of Pegasus."
有天蝎座驾驶，我们永远不会输。
With Scorpus driving
them, we'll never lose.
当然，除非，
Unless, of course,
赔率会让亏损变得更有利可图
the odds make
losing more profitable.
还有一件事
And one other thing.
我想正式成为你的客户，
I'd like to formally
become your client,
为了更好地服务于您的利益。
in order to better
serve your interests.
我的委托人
My client.
这是一大步。
That is a big step.
责任是双向的。
The responsibility
goes both ways.
上上下下
Up and down.
我会考虑的
I'll consider it.
还有你的另一个提议
And your other offer as well.
走了
Leave now.
兄弟们！
Brothers!
我要去小便。
Gotta take a piss.
啊！我的天啊！看你是不是要在我完事后走。
Ah! See if you gotta
go after I'm done.
我的珍珠，不然我就把它切了。
My pearls, or I cut it off.
我只剩一个了。我发誓
I only have one left. I swear.
剩下的我用来还债了。
I used the rest to pay debts.
只剩下这些了。
That's all that's left.
在地上
On the ground.
埃利亚，你要我说多少遍
Elia, how many times
do I have to say it?
又不是永远。我们很快就会一起回去。
It's not forever. We'll all
go back together soon.
具体是什么时候
When, exactly?
在你做马夫而不是马夫之后？
After you're grooms
instead of stable hands?
在你开始开车之后？
After you start driving?
给它一个机会。两周后，再做决定。
Give it a chance. One
fortnight, then decide.
号
No.
你们两个都骗了我。
You've lied to me. Both of you.
你从没想过要回家，是吗？
You never intended
to go home, did you?
好好照顾费罗。夏天的大麦，
Take good care of Ferox.
Barley in the summer,
别忘了带他去牧场
and don't forget to
take him to the pasture.
只刷水，不刷油。
Water brushes only, never oil.
胡萝卜换牙齿
Carrots for his teeth.
伊利亚来了
Elia. Come.
快，来！
Quickly, come!
费洛斯
Ferox.
靠近一点
Come closer.
是的，是时候了。
Yes, it is that time.
自凯撒·奥古斯都以来，没有一个皇帝
Since Caesar
Augustus, no emperor
由一个真正的儿子继承
has been succeeded
by a true son.
他们都被养子跟踪
They've all been
followed by adopted sons
或者是篡位者直到现在，直到我。
or by usurpers.
Until now, until me.
哈你
Huh.
看看你们两个
Look at the two of you.
两人都有能力取代我的位置。
Both more than capable
of taking my place.
提图斯，那个士兵，和我一样
Titus, the soldier, like myself,
一系列的胜利。
with a string of victories.
图密善，我们有洞察力和敏锐的政治家，
And Domitian, our politician
of insight and subtlety,
在我们不在的时候很擅长应付元老院
so adept at handling
the Senate in our absence
还帮我固定了教长椅
and helping me
secure the curule chair.
这是一个艰难的选择。
It is a difficult choice.
但是没有什么比
But nothing, nothing
is more important
更重要的罗马了
than protecting
our beloved Rome.
我们的外敌很危险，
Our foreign enemies
are dangerous,
我们在罗马的敌人也很危险
and our enemies here in
Rome itself are also dangerous.
准备牺牲这座城市来实现他们的野心。
Ready to sacrifice this city
on the altar of their ambition.
但在这两者中，
But of the two,
我们的外敌
our foreign enemies,
帕提亚人，高卢人，不列颠人，匈奴人
the Parthians, the Gauls,
the Britons, the Huns,
他们才是更大的危险
they are the greater danger.
因此，我们认为，
Therefore,
士兵必须坐在牧师椅上。
a soldier must sit
on the curule chair.
提图斯你将成为皇帝
Titus, you will be Emperor.
图密善？
Domitian?
我会尽我所能为我哥哥服务
I will serve my brother
in every way I can.
那很好.
That is good.
门！
Door!
你现在罢工吗？
Do you strike now?
对抗提图斯的军团？
Against Titus' legions?
他的财富和禁卫军的忠诚
His riches and the loyalty
of the Praetorian Guards?
号让提图斯相信他赢了
No. Let Titus believe he's won.
我要用我得到的武器和他战斗。
I will fight him with the
weapons I've been granted.
不。我一定看起来像
No, no, no. I must look like
亚历山大大帝，不是街头妓女。
Alexander the Great,
not a street whore.
我需要一些更戏剧性的东西来装饰我的隆重登场。
I need something much more
dramatic for my grand entrance.
天蝎座大帝
Scorpus the Great.
自己派系的司机。- 是吗-是的
Driver of his own faction. Yes?
出去！
Out!
嗯？
Hmm?
这就是你所谓的谨慎吗
Is this what you call discreet?
一旦我们得到图密善的批准消息就会传开。
Word will get out once
we get Domitian's approval.
如果我们得到批准。
If we get approval.
来吧，他在马厩等我们
Come, he's meeting
us at the stables
去看安达卢西亚人
to look at the Andalusians.
- 我操！- 加弗罗斯去找医生了
- Fuck!
- Gavros went to go get a physician.
- 大人. - 大人.
- My lord.
为什么没人告诉我？
Why didn't someone tell me?
图密善，他来了。外面
Domitian, he's here. Outside.
就像我说的，操！
As I said, fuck!
好吧，我去引开他。
All right, I'll divert him.
拉上窗帘。去，闭上眼睛。
Close the curtains.
Go, close them.
来吧
Come on.
来帮帮我
Come, help me.
这里.
Here.
弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯
Flavius Domitianus.
那些长着飞马翅膀的马在哪里？
Where are these horses
with the wings of Pegasus?
首先，来点食物或酒怎么样？
First, how about some
food, or wine, perhaps?
号
No.
女孩，或者男孩？
Girls, or maybe boys?
我在想，马厩并没有展示他们最好的一面。
I was thinking, the stables
don't show them at their best.
你应该看看他们在赛道上的表现，
You should see
them on the track,
- 跑步，也许明天。- Tenax！
- running, perhaps tomorrow?
- Tenax!
我没时间跟你说这个。他们在哪里？
I have no time for
this. Where are they?
我很了解马，能看到它们奔跑或马厩。
I know horses well enough
to see them running or stabled.
大人.
My lord.
弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯，你让我们荣誉。
Flavius Domitianus,
you honor us.
天蝎座。
Scorpus.
而且很清醒已经印象深刻了。这是其中之一吗
And sober. Impressed
already. Is this one of them?
是的，是的，费罗克斯。率先
Yes, yes, Ferox. The lead.
他为什么被吊着？
Why is he in a sling?
这是西班牙人的技术殿下
It's a Spanish
technique, Your Highness.
在长时间的上坡跑后，我们把它们吊起来放了一天。
We sling them for a
day after a long uphill run.
这使他们在平地上更快。
It makes them
faster on the flat.
是的我听说过这个技术。
Yes. Yes, I've heard
of this technique.
其他人呢？
Where are the others?
在牧场。
At pasture.
外面
Outside.
没事的
It's okay.
马克西姆斯马戏团现在有五个派系。
Circus Maximus
now has five factions.
你们每人将拥有四分之一。
Each of you will
own one quarter.
我对其中一半的所有权将继续保留。
My ownership of one half
shall remain in the shadows.
- 如你所愿- 听我的命令。
- As you wish.
- As I command.
别让我失望
Do not disappoint me.
殿下
Your Highness.
还有一件事
One more thing.
我决定让你成为我的客户之一。
I've decided to make
you one of my clients.
你让我感到荣誉。
You honor me.
我将为你的利益服务，直到我死。
Till my death, I will
serve your interests.
如果对我合适，我会保护你的。
And should it suit me,
I may protect yours.
跟我
With me.
奥甘德斯，这是最好的。
Augendus, the best there is.
他曾经是绿党的兽医。
He was once
veterinarius for the Greens.
你是对的，加夫罗斯。肯定是茄属植物
You were right, Gavros.
Most definitely nightshade.
你能为他们做什么？
What can you do for them?
埋了他们。
Bury them.
我没心情开玩笑。
I'm not in the mood for jokes.
你能做的很少。
There's little you can do.
一个马格纳斯可能会说，把乌鸦在他们的摊位三个晚上。
A magnus might say put crows
in their stalls for three nights.
用铃铛把奥奇的灵魂从他们的肝脏里召唤出来。
And use bells to call out the
Orci spirits from their livers.
我可不想拿我的命去赌。尽你所能
I'm not going to bet my life
on that one. Do what you can.
没有人见过这个。
No one has seen this.
如果你告诉任何人，
If you tell a single
fucking person,
你会死得很惨你明白吗？
you will die in ways you cannot
imagine. Do you understand?
是的
Yes.
记住你唯一要害怕的人
Remember, the only
person you have to fear
比图密善更重要的是我
more than Domitian, is me.
我们明白，先生。我们在这里什么也没看到。
We understand, sir. We
have seen nothing here.
你们两个
You two.
安德里亚，埃利亚，来。
Andria, Elia, come.
好吧，弟弟。
All right, little brother.
你赢了这太危险了
You win. This is
getting too dangerous.
我说我们沿着玩到天黑，
I say we play along until dark,
然后溜出城
and then slip out of the city.
- 去哪里？- 任何地方，除了这里。
- To go where?
- Anywhere, other than here.
- 回家- 我不会让我们的马去死的
- Home.
- I'm not going to leave our horses to die.
现在他想留下来。
Now he wants to stay.
这些马还是小马驹的时候我们就养大了。
We have reared these horses
ever since they were foals.
我爱他们，我不会丢下他们的。
I love them, and I'm not
going to leave them behind.
皇帝的儿子看到我们了
The Emperor's son has seen us.
如果我们逃跑能逃多远？
How far would we get if we run?
我们别无选择
We have no option.
我们加入天蝎座和Tenax。
We throw in with
Scorpus and Tenax.
去找警卫。我会再送些过去
And get guards. I'll send more.
这是谁干的？
Who did this?
我也正想问你呢。
I was about to ask
you the same thing.
我没告诉任何人。
I told no one.
除了你那该死的裁缝和谁知道还有谁安东尼娅，也许？
Except your bloody tailor and who
knows who else. Antonia, perhaps?
图密善有奴隶和随从。他们会说话
Domitian has slaves
and attendants. They talk.
太晚了
It's too late now.
我参加比赛的第一年，
My first year of racing,
红军的领头马中了龙葵毒
the Reds' lead horse was
poisoned with nightshade.
卡尔杜斯医生用黄色的灰烬治愈了它。
Physician Caldus
cured it with yellow ash.
黄色的灰烬是毒药。它会比治愈更快地杀死你。
Yellow ash is poison. It
will kill quicker than cure.
这对Caldus很有效。
It worked for Caldus.
你能抓住他吗？他在哪里？
Can you get him? Where is he?
庞贝。我去吧
Pompeii. I'll go.
你和他一起去保证他的安全
You go with him. Keep him safe.
别让人看见。
Try not to be seen.
我们去找些新鲜的马。
Let's get some fresh horses.
天蝎座！天蝎座
Scorpus! Scorpus!
- 警卫- 是的先生
- Guards.
- Yes, sir.
Tenax我已经付过你的人钱了。
Tenax. I paid your men already.
- 两周前。- 我不收。
- A fortnight ago.
- I'm not collecting.
我请客龙葵
I'm buying. Nightshade.
我不卖毒药。
I don't sell poisons.
Anymore.
我把所有的都卖了。
I sold all I had.
对谁？
To whom?
我知道你给我的马下毒。谁雇你的
I know that you poisoned
my horses. Who hired you?
无论如何你都会杀了我。
You are going to kill me anyway.
我为什么要告诉你？
Why should I tell you?
别那么肯定我会杀了你。
Don't be so sure
I'm going to kill you.
你活着对我更有用。
You might be more
use to me alive.
只有他自己知道。
Salto there, only he knew.
他和垃圾堆里的某个人说话。
He spoke to someone in a litter.
- 当我穿过广场。- 描述一下垃圾。
- When I was across the square.
- Describe the litter.
真不错金色和绿色条纹，木柄。
Fancy. Gold and green
stripes, with wooden handles.
记住我的仁慈
Remember my mercy.
找出那垃圾是谁的。
Find out who owns that litter.
- 死了多少人- 这是第一个。
- How many have died?
- This is the first.
到目前为止，我救了其他人。
I have saved the
others thus far.
加夫罗斯
Gavros.
去买其他的马。
Find other horses to buy.
所有的好货都归派系所有。
All the good stock is
owned by the factions.
你找到的任何东西都不会那么好。
Anything you find
will not be as good.
他们会活下来的
They'll be alive.
没有更多.
No more.
我们收拾行李准备离开
We pack and we'll
be ready to leave
安德里亚一回来就去
as soon as Andria returns.
我告诉过你了。我不会走的
I've told you. I'm not leaving.
你还是个孩子你一直都是个孩子。
You're a child. You've
always been a child.
自从我们的母亲生你时去世，安德里亚和我就把你宠坏了.
Andria and I have spoiled you since the
moment our mother died giving birth to you.
好吧走了
Fine. Go.
妈妈，你没事吧？
Mother, are you all right?
- 我能帮你吗- 好的麻烦您
- Can I help you with that?
- Yes, please.
- 我们说什么？- 谢谢
- What do we say?
- Thank you.
乌拉乌拉，起来。
Woola. Woola, get up.
就是这个
That's the one.
来吧，让我们看看它去哪里。
Come on, let's
see where it goes.
让开
Make way.
金色和绿色条纹。这绝对是垃圾。
Gold and green stripes.
This is definitely the litter.
去找Tenax
Go get Tenax.
是的当然为了你，我会冲。
Yes, of course.
For you, I'll rush.
我可以在一个月内准备好。
I can have them ready
in less than a month.
我没有一个月的时间，我肯定有两天。
I don't have a month,
I'm sure I have two days.
这些呢？
What about these?
哦这是我最好的作品
Oh. These are my best work.
- 我可以给你做一双一模一样的。- 我要这些。
- I can build a pair exactly like these for you.
- I'll take these.
不，这些是莱托的。他为他们订购了氙气。
No, these are Leto's. He
ordered them for Xenon.
他们现在是我的了重新粉刷。
They're mine now. Repaint them.
我不能我
I can't.
我们找到垃圾了！
We found the litter!
重新粉刷。
Repaint them.
什么颜色？
What color?
围过来，围过来。
Gather round, gather round.
拍卖会就要开始了。
The auction is about to begin.
让开！
Make way there!
好吧
All right.
作为我们的第一个祭品。
For our first offering.
看看这个英国人。不仅漂亮，
Look at this Briton.
Not only beautiful,
但她做的菜都很好吃
but she cooks all
the wonderful dishes
英国人因此而闻名
for which the Britons
are so famous.
谁给我100塞斯特斯？
Who'll give me 100 sesterces?
噢，来吧。那就80。
Oh come on. Eighty, then.
好极了这个是你的。
Excellent. This one's yours.
快过来接她。
Step right up and
come and get her.
下一个，是一个工作狂。
Up next, this
workhorse of a girl.
适合任何类型的耕作。
Suitable for either
type of ploughing.
谁给我50块？
Who'll give me 50?
我给你50.
I'll give you 50.
50在这里过来拿钥匙
Fifty over here.
Come and get the key.
现在，我们的主要吸引力。
And now, for our
main attraction.
努米底亚姐妹篇。
A pair of Numidian sisters.
作为一套或单独出售。有人出价吗？
Sold as a set or
individually. Any bids?
一百块
One hundred.
One-eighty.
两百块
Two hundred.
我听说这个是处女。
I'm told this one is a virgin.
没有人或野兽碰过。
Untouched by man or beast.
谁给我250？
Who'll give me 250?
有人出价吗？四百？
Now any bids? 400?
五
Five.
- 六百- 七百块
- Six hundred.
- Seven hundred.
八
Eight.
三千塞斯特斯。
Three thousand sesterces.
成交三千塞斯特斯。
Sold! For 3,000 sesterces.
我的话。
My word.
快来拿你的东西。
Come and get your goods.
妈妈！
Mother!
有点同情心吧。
Have some pity.
- 求你了- 不好意思
- Please.
- I'm sorry.
妈妈！妈妈！
Mother! Mother!
下一个，她的妹妹。
And next, her sister.
妈妈！
Mother!
也许不是处女，但坚固和良好的形成。
Perhaps not a virgin, but
sturdy and well formed.
五百
Five hundred.
我出八百。
I bid 800.
500块卖给Tenax
Sold to Tenax for 500.
不，不我出800.
No, no, no. I bid 800.
抱歉，我没听见。
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
给你，给你，1000.
Here, here, 1,000.
她已经被卖了。
She's already sold.
号号
No. No.
1000，我加倍你的出价。
One thousand, I double your bid.
抱歉，交易已经完成了。
Sorry, the deal is done.
塔莉亚你先出去
Talia, leave us.
坐下
Sit.
我说了坐下。
I said sit.
你带我走之后，
After you take me,
你迟早会睡着的。
sooner or later
you will fall asleep.
如果你这么做了，我会割断你的喉咙。
And when you do,
I will slit your throat.
你要割断我的喉咙？
You're going to slit my throat?
我拥有你。你是我的奴隶
I own you. You are my slave.
我可以对你为所欲为。
I can do whatever
I want with you.
你不会放弃的。
You don't give up.
我是她妈妈。
I am her mother.
我女朋友
My girl.
奥拉，我在这里。
Aura, I'm here.
我已经告诉你了她是销售
I already told you.
She's not for sale.
一切都是销售在合适的价格。
Everything is for
sale at the right price.
不是她
Not her.
你为什么买她？
Why did you buy her?
我想知道买下你另一个女儿的人的事。
I need to know things about the
person who bought your other daughter.
我明白了.
I see.
你想利用这个女儿
You seek to use this daughter
作为我另一个女儿的中间人来监视你的敌人
as a go-between to my other
daughter to spy on your enemy.
我有别的选择。
I have an alternative.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
我会做你的中间人
I will be your go-between.
但你不能碰她。
But you don't touch her.
等这一切结束了不管是什么
And when this is
over, whatever it is,
你允许我买下她
you allow me to buy her.
以你为代价。
At your cost.
号
No.
当这一切都完成后，
When all this is done,
我会考虑以任何我喜欢的价格把她卖给你。
I will consider selling her to
you for whatever price I like.
我需要住宿。
I need lodging.
我在后面有个房间。
I have a room at the back.
你可以和你女儿住几晚。
You can stay with your
daughter for a couple of nights.
我叫卡拉。
My name is Cala.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
嘿嘘
Hey, shh!
水，不是毒药。
Water, not poison.
你对我做得很好。
You did well against me.
- 你想干什么？- 好的
- What do you want?
- A deal.
你看到那个大块头角斗士在看我们吗？
Did you see the big
gladiator watching us?
脖子上有标记的巨人
The giant one with the
markings on his neck.
- 是的- 他是Flamma。
- Yes.
- He is Flamma.
他会杀了我的
He's going to kill me.
可怜你。
Pity you.
是的可怜可怜我吧。
Yes. Pity me.
从我小时候起，
See, from the
time I was a child,
我一直都是最大最强壮最快的
I've always been the
biggest, strongest, the fastest.
作为一个战士，我总是杀得很轻松。
As a warrior, I have
always killed with ease.
也许你会让这位弗拉玛大吃一惊
Perhaps you'll
surprise this Flamma.
号
No.
他要杀我易如反掌。
He's going to kill me with ease.
他比我高大，比我敏捷，比我强壮，
He's bigger than me, faster
than me, stronger than me,
他有无穷的技巧
and he has an
endless well of tricks,
任何一个都能让我的肚子被剑刺穿
any of which can put a
sword through my belly.
这跟我有什么关系
What is this to me?
那个商人法里德
The trader, Farid.
他说你徒手杀死了一头狮子。
He said that you killed
a lion without a weapon.
这是我对罗马人撒的谎
That is a lie I tell the Romans
被雇来打猎
to get hired for their hunts.
我曾经在没有武器的情况下杀死过一只豹子。
I did once kill a leopard
without a weapon.
它几乎完全长大了，
It was almost full-grown,
有时豹子也能杀死狮子
and sometimes a
leopard can kill a lion.
这就像我杀死了一头狮子。
So that is almost
like me killing a lion.
差不多了
Almost.
也许在这里面有一些小东西
Perhaps in that, there
is some little thing
我可以用来对付火焰。
I can use against Flamma.
你所知道的，什么都不是，
With what you know,
which is nothing,
你在竞技场一天都活不下去
you will not survive
one day in the arena.
但如果你告诉我你所知道的
But if you tell me what you know
和比你更大更强壮的动物战斗
about fighting animals
bigger and stronger than you,
我可以教你我们的武器
I can teach you our weapons.
给你一个生存的机会，
Give you a chance to survive,
梦见木剑
and dream of the wooden sword.
木剑？
The wooden sword?
自由
Freedom.
如果角斗士能很好地取悦观众，
If a gladiator entertains
the crowd well enough,
群众可以要求把木剑给他。
the crowd can demand he
be given the wooden sword.
把他带出这个地方。
Which takes him
out of this place.
- 有价值的人。- 你的呢？
- The worthy ones.
- And what is yours?
去解救我的姐妹篇们，去杀罗马人。
To free my sisters,
and kill Romans.
可惜我们杀不了他们。
Pity we can't kill them all.
那个监视我们的人呢
What of the one
who was watching us?
眼睛像土狼的那个？
The one with the
eyes of a hyena?
毫米图密善
Mm. Domitian.
他是皇帝维斯帕先的儿子。
He is the son of the
Emperor Vespasian.
那他就行
Then he will do.
- 你说什么？
What?
你想先杀图密善？
You want to start
with killing Domitian?
那我们就这么做
Then that's what we will do.